Let us briefly take a look at an example algorithm,
让我们简要地看一下示例算法，
and how you might follow its steps yourself.
以及如何自己执行其步骤。
We don't need to know anything about programming to do these steps,
我们不需要对编程一无所知就能完成这些步骤，
we just need to be able to do some math,
我们只需要能够做一些数学运算，
and keep careful track of what we're doing.
并仔细跟踪我们在做什么。
This algorithm does not accomplish a really useful task,
这个算法并不能完成一项真正有用的任务，
but gives us a simple example to start from.
但给了我们一个简单的例子来开始。
The algorithm says, "Given a non-negative integer N," so it is
算法说：“给定一个非负整数 N”，所以它在
parameterized over N. We need a value of N to actually do these steps,
N 上进行参数化。我们需要一个值 N 才能真正执行这些步骤，
so let's pick N equals two.
所以让我们选择 N 等于二。
We're also going to want a place to write down the output that the algorithm produces,
我们还需要一个地方来写下算法产生的输出，也
that is, everything that we are told to write down,
就是说，我们被告知要写下的所有内容，
we will write in this output box.
我们将在这个输出框中写下来。
We need to keep track of where we are,
我们需要跟踪自己的位置，
so we are going to use this green arrow to remember what step we are currently on.
因此我们将使用这个绿色箭头来记住我们目前正在走哪一步。
We'll start at the start.
我们将从头开始。
The step right after the arrow says to make a variable called X,
箭头后面的步骤说要创建一个名为 X 的变量，
and set it equaled to N plus two.
然后将其设置为等于 N 加二。
N is two, and two plus two is four,
N 是二，二加二等于四，
so we want to note that X is initially four.
所以我们要注意的是，X 最初是四。
Our next step calls for us to count from zero to
下一步要求我们从零到
N. We will want to give a name to the number we are counting,
北计数。我们需要为正在计数的数字起一个名字，
so that we can use it in our other steps.
这样我们就可以在其他步骤中使用它。
Here, we decided to call it i.
在这里，我们决定称之为 i。
As we count, we are going to repeat steps.
随着时间的推移，我们将重复步骤。
We've used indentation here to indicate
我们在这里使用缩进来表示
which steps are repeated for each number we count,
我们计算的每个数字都要重复哪些步骤
as well as explicitly noting in the step after that you do it,
，并在接下来的步骤中明确注明
when you finish counting.
何时完成计数。
We'll start with i being zero,
我们从 i 为零开始，
since that is the first number we said to count.
因为那是我们说要计算的第一个数字。
Our next step says to write down X times i.
我们的下一步是写下 X 倍 i。
Four times zero is zero,
四次零等于零，
so we write down zero.
所以我们写下零。
Our next step says for us to update the value of X.
下一步是让我们更新 X 的值。
What is its new value?
它的新值是什么？
Four plus zero times two is four,
四加零乘以二等于四
so, we would update it to be four.
，所以，我们会将其更新为四。
It's already four, which is fine,
已经是四了，没关系，
we just keep its value as four.
我们只要把它的值保持为四即可。
Now, we have reached the end of the steps that we said to do as we count.
现在，我们已经走到了我们所说的按我们计算的步骤的尽头。
We need to go back and count the next number,
我们需要回去数下一个数字，
so we move our arrow back to the top of the step we were doing for each number,
所以我们将箭头移回为每个数字所做的步骤的顶部，
and make i the next number we would count,
然后将 i 设为下一个我们要计算的数字，
in this case, one.
在本例中为一个。
Now, we begin doing these steps again with i having the value one.
现在，我们又开始执行这些步骤了，我的价值是 1。
What is X times i now?
我现在是 X 次是多少？
Four times one is four,
四乘一等于四，
so we write down the number four in our output.
所以我们在输出中写下数字四。
Next, we are going to update X again, this time,
接下来，我们将再次更新 X，这一
X plus i times N evaluates to six,
次，X 加 i 乘以 N 的计算结果为 6，
so we are going to change the value of X from four to six.
因此我们要将 X 的值从 4 更改为 6。
We've again reached the end of our repeated steps,
我们又到了重复步骤的尽头，
so we need to count our next number.
所以我们需要计算下一个数字。
We'd go back to the top,
我们会回到顶部，
and then count our next value which is two,
然后计算下一个值，也就是二，
and make that the value of i.
然后把它当作 i 的值。
We said to count from zero to N,
我们说从零计到 N，
and N is two, so are we done counting?
N 是二，那么我们算完了吗？
In these steps, we said to include both ends,
在这些步骤中，我们说要包括两端，
so we're going to do these steps when i has the value two.
所以当我的值为二时，我们将执行这些步骤。
So, we go in and do the repeated steps one more time.
所以，我们进去再做一次重复的步骤。
Now, X times i has the value 12,
现在，X 次 i 的值为 12，
so we write down 12 in our output and we go to the next step.
所以我们在输出中写下 12 然后进入下一步。
Our next step says to update the value of X again,
我们的下一步是再次更新 X 的值，计算
evaluating X plus i times N,
X 加 i 乘以 N，
we get 10 this time,
这次我们得到 10，
so we update the value of X to be 10,
所以我们将 X 的值更新为 10，
and move past that step.
然后越过该步骤。
Once more, we've reached the end of the steps we want to repeat as we count,
再一次，我们已经到了要重复的步骤的尽头，
so we return to the step where we said to count.
所以我们又回到了我们说要计数的步骤。
When we return here,
当我们回到这里时，
we look at our steps and realize that we've already
我们看看我们的步骤，意识到我们已经
counted all of the numbers we were supposed to,
计算了所有应该计算的数字，
zero, one and two.
零、一和二。
So, we're done counting.
所以，我们已经算完了。
Now, we want to go to the steps after we finish counting and do them.
现在，我们要在完成计数之后进入步骤并执行这些步骤。
This one says to write down the value of X. X currently has value 10,
这个说要写下 X 的值。X 当前的值为 10，
so we write that in our output.
所以我们在输出中写下来。
Now, our arrow is at the end of our steps.
现在，我们的箭在脚步的尽头。
There's nothing left to do, so we're done.
没有什么可做的，所以我们已经完成了。
Zero, four, 12, 10 is the sequence of numbers that this algorithm wanted us to generate,
零、四、12、10 是这个算法想要我们生成的数字序列，
for N equals two which we see in our output box.
因为 N 等于二，我们在输出框中看到。